The danger could be the
stock remaining at this
corrected price for a long period of time.  That is,
enter now, correct
the action another 20% 30% and stay here
for a long time.
Hello dears and welcome to
a new video on the
Grow Your Wealth YouTube channel, here where we try to keep you
updated with everything that is happening
in the financial area, in the area of
our companies of interest,
financial reports, the
resumption of the conflict between America
and Iran, oil prices, the blockade of the
Straits of Hormuz and the Red Sea.
We discuss all of this.  We would like
to thank
our members who support our work and
our partners at XTB.
Yes, thank you for joining
us for another episode.  We hope to
debate interesting things and
gain something from this hour you
spend with us.
We thank our members for being
with us and
we try to prepare them.  We have prepared them
in advance for what is coming in the
capital market and we are trying to support them during
this delicate period through
daily materials and perhaps even
additional materials in the next
period, certain videos in which we will have
to debate the mindset part more
.
And don't forget to tell them to
like and subscribe because
most don't do that.
Yes, dear ones, subscribe to
our channel, press the like button,
for the vast majority the team told us
no, don't do that.  So let's get
started.  And if you want to subscribe
to our newsletter, in which
every Monday we send to the people
who are subscribed the introductory material
of the week, which is taken from
our materials written for
our members.  Basically, you can see a
teaser of what a community material looks like
.  There you have all the details,
the link is in the description and I think
for those of you who are interested in
coming to our community at some point,
which is currently closed and
we are making a waiting list, you can
see a short material about what is
happening there.  We start from the
European area, here where the central bank has its
meeting on monetary interest rates
and what happens?  We have a hold after
last session we had a
slight increase in interest rates.  At the moment
we have stagnation and in the end it is very
interesting what the European Central Bank is doing
because it is the second most
powerful in this monetary area.  We look
very closely at the decisions she
makes.  How do you see this stagnation and what can we
expect in the
near future?
It's a welcome stagnation because the
European Central Bank was a
little hasty with rate increases.
We know that this stagnation comes after an
increase in the previous session.
It's a time,
let's say, when they want to test
people's return home from
vacations and the World Cup and other
events they attended and the
start of spending in their countries of
origin.  We'll see how
this plays out, but I don't think
Europe is in danger of
inflation rising.  Even though prices are
still rising, Europeans do not consume as much as
Americans do.
Yes, but from this point of view,
I think the European Central Bank
made a good decision.  Now we will see
how things will evolve by the end
of the year.  For now, stagnation is what was
needed.
We have a somewhat predictable situation,
but at the same time surprising
for the markets.  The rekindling of the conflict
between
America and Iran.  We have some blockades
going on around the Strait of Hormuz that are
quite well known.   The
problematic situation is that the
Houthi group is trying to block the
Swedish Channel and the Red Sea.
Yes, there is another strait there.
Babel Mandeb.   Yes.
which, if
blocked, would cut off this access to
Europe.  In
practice, Asia and Europe would no longer have
such good access.  they should make a
detour around Africa and then
return through the Strait of Gibraltar.
And then what I'm curious about right now is that
something that would extend the duration of
a trip on oil or
cargo ships from Asia to Europe
would also increase transport insurance.   Yes.
And I would like my colleagues to insert
the material here so that you can see
that map better.  I'm curious how
you see this idea of
conflict at the moment, and I was asking you
before we even gave our recommendation if you think it's
viable that this threat that
Donald Trump is
repeatedly mentioning now, when he said he was close to making the
decision to attack Iran,
could end up with
even a ground attack.  We know this
is the most undesirable thing, but it seems to me
that the strings are slowly being stretched so tight
that, God forbid,
this could happen.   Yes.
What we need to know is that this
Houthi group is supported by
Iran.
Absolute.  Yes.
And they are trying by any means to
strangle oil traffic,
oil exports, but also the traffic of goods
from Asia to Europe.
This is something very serious that is happening.
We mentioned here that it is
unlikely that the
calm in the Persian Gulf will
last very long.  I mentioned it a
few times even when we
had a positive surprise with a
treaty signing on Trump's birthday, the
signing of a treaty between America and
Iran.  We don't believe in such a thing and we never will.
America is pursuing its
plan further.
From my point of view, America
is currently in a situation where it
exports oil.  So any blockage
of the Strait of Hormuz does
not harm America, it harms other
states.  as a complement, how beautifully
Ukraine,
which is one of
Palantir's entertainers, fits into this strategy
by attacking
Russian oil refineries with drones at the very moment
when the only
viable trade route is from America
to the rest of the globe.   Yes
, yes, America.  That's why we've been mentioning
here for some time [tense voice] that
America's geopolitical
and military strategy has changed, and
national security has changed very, very
much with the arrival of
Trump.   I
don't think the Brick countries have the courage
now to declare anything against the dollar
or against America, or things are going the way
America wants
with the necessary risks, with the
necessary conflicts, let's say.
All we hope is that this conflict in
Iran ends as soon as possible.
Also, the conflict in Ukraine,
if possible, would be perfect if it
ended around the elections in the
United States.  Maybe yes, maybe no, we don't
know.  We want this as soon as possible
.
But what is happening in the Persian Gulf
will not last.
Always
[trained voice] as long as
the state of Israel and Muslim countries exist, it will not
be peaceful.
Donald Trump's double tariffs.
In case you missed this, I don't know,
tariff series, Donald Trump is going to
start it again.  I'm trying to make a
topic interesting that we
as investors don't necessarily like and isn't
necessarily
desirable.  It's just that right now
, as you were talking about
America's strategy earlier, it seems that
America's strategy right now is
full domination over everything that means
economic adversaries who at some point
raised suspicion over the
dollar,
America's most important weapon.  They have
raised suspicions about
America's supremacy as a world leader
and the response is always very
brutal.  Even if in the end we end up
with American citizens suffering and
companies subsequently benefiting from
some taxes that they receive back from the
American government, we
realize that those who are affected are
America's economic adversaries and that
is more than more than visible.
We see problems in the Asian area.  We hope that
some
open conflict fronts will not intervene,
as it seems to be fashionable in recent years in
that area, but I'm curious how the
tariffs are looking at the moment and
this strategy is starting to take shape,
a bit too aggressive for a lot of the
American population, but it seems to be
taking shape, it seems to calm the waters a bit
.  In Russia, we see
problems with
fuel at the pump.  The first time
Russia buys from India, we see that
China is much more docile with America, much
more willing to negotiate.  The area of ​​the six, let's
not say there are quite big problems in
many, many places there and I was
curious how you see
this new strategy with tariffs, do you see it
being implementable or is it more of a
statement to scare the markets?  not
necessarily to scare the markets, but wants
everyone to respect what they established
in the first round, so to speak
.
April 2025. Yes, I believe that America is
following its strategy going forward,
both in the geopolitical and
macroeconomic areas, because it must
force all those who initially
agreed to invest in America to do so
.
If there are still companies or states that
have not yet started certain projects to
develop production facilities
in America,
hm,
on the occasion of this warning, let's
call it that, they might do it,
speed up the work,
speed up the work a little,
speed up the investments a little because
Trump, apart from this year, still has
two more years of office and must
achieve everything he proposed by the
end of his term.
He has to leave a very
strong legacy behind and at a time when
certain major companies are creating
production facilities in America, they can't
really get out of there.  I mean, it's
hard to bring them in, but once you've brought them in,
they're captive.  Because if they want to
continue selling in America, they need to
keep jobs and even
increase production capacities.  Yes,
it's a good strategy for America and
this has been seen since last year.
Let's see how it will end.
And as you well know, this podcast
is supported by our partners
at XTB.  XTB, which is this broker
that gives us access to foreign markets, a
broker with residence in Romania, with
support in Romania and with a program in
which they offer a
free course for people who sign up with
them on the platform, are new, create
a new account and use the
code Gyw as a reference.
When they create this account,
if you use our code, you will receive
a free course for people who
are just starting out and want to
understand how this area of
investment works and what its implications are.  You will
find all the details on the link in the
description with the mention XTB.  We continue with the
Google report, a report
that at least caught my attention, it seems to me to be
a negative period that
Google is going through and it's important to
mention this.  The first report with
negative free cash flow,
I think, in about 10-15 years.  It's
a negative free cash flow that comes from the
very large investments in the cloud and
artificial intelligence areas that Google is
making to remain competitive in the
market.  At the same time, I was watching that
Google recently raised capital from the market
through an issuance of shares,
convertible bonds.
Convertible bonds.  In the end, it
's still a dilution, but it would still be
a dilution
if those people wanted
to convert
those bonds into
specific Google shares.
Now, the question I wanted to
ask you about the Google report, how did
you see it and how do you think
Google is positioning itself?  What is
their real strategy?  What do you see that the vast
majority of people don't
notice?
I'm a little contrarian about the
feedback the market is giving to that
Google action.  Why?  Because I realize
that we are in a period
of transition in which massive investments are being made
in the AI ​​area.  Google is accelerating
strongly and we have been mentioning for a very long
time that Google's Deep Mind division
is among, if not the most
performing.  Among the most
efficient, if not the most
efficient.
And I believe at this point that if
Google stock corrects below $300 it
will become a very
important opportunity for investors
starting certain portfolios.  And I can
mention here on YouTube that when
we open up
our community to new members,
those with a moderate dynamic risk profile
will be empowered to buy
Google aggressively.
Google at under $300 is a
very big opportunity for the future because it will
remain one of the largest companies
and will increase the share price a lot
at least in the next two to three years and even
beyond, even if
Google also goes through a
fairly large correction or a crash somewhere in
four to six years when there will be this crash
in the market and Google
will have a correction, but until
then, I think the share price will
increase quite a lot after the correction you are
going through now. As for
me, [snoring] please excuse me, I am
going through a delicate moment of
crisis due to an allergic rhinitis that I have.
And if you see me, you see me like this with
a little more teary eyes or you see me holding my
hand to my nose, I really
have a pretty serious problem.  But we're doing our best
to film this video
because that's what we promised we would
always do every week and no
matter what conditions we're
going through, even if we're away on
vacation or even if we have
health problems or something else, we try to
be here face to face with you
every week.  A very
good report after a long, long time at
Intel.   Yes.
a report that doesn't impress the
market much.  This is also because
Intel has had quite a large
and quite aggressive evolution
lately.
With this whole
semiconductor sector,
I was looking at the fact that there is a
fairly high demand in this area for CPUs
and Intel also participates in this duopoly.
Intel and AMD also participate very
well and I was curious how you reviewed the
report from Intel which,
although very good, did not bring
spectacular growth but if I'm not mistaken,
we are somewhere around 4%.
Now before the market opens,
yes, the report is very good, but
just like Service Now which
reported a good report on Wednesday, it
came in a negative market context.   Right now
we're filming on Friday around
1:00 PM, preparing for some
pretty strong strikes on Iran from
America and Israel.
Market sentiment is negative.
We will close the week in
negative territory, in my opinion, because
even if there will be a few stocks that
open positive today at 4:30 by the
end of the session, because we will have
a likely fiery weekend,
stocks will correct.  Intel
very good reporting.  It is a company
in which the American state invests.  is
a company that received a boost
thanks to this investment.  A lot of
contracts started to be traded,
zero DT contracts and call options with
long maturities on Intel were bought, and then the
share price experienced a
fairly aggressive increase.
Intel is going through a positive moment, but
let's move on from these two
months, August and September, and see
how Intel will emerge from this
correction, which will be a correction across the
entire market.  We'll see
which sectors the tech money will flow to
, especially from
semiconductors, but I think that when the
market returns, Intel will receive the same
positive attention from
investors.  One report that wasn't very
impressive was the one from Tesla, and we
decided to discuss
Tesla's report as well.  In the idea that, although we'll
do it quite subtly, Tesla didn't have
a very poor reporting, but again, as
in the case of the magnificent ones, there are
some very large investments that
Tesla is making in this area of
new facilities, production facilities,
energy megapacks, the area for creating
Optimus robots, and then
all these huge investments that
Tesla has, put pressure
on the financial report, on the balance sheet,
on the cash that the company retains, and
then there
are small negative discrepancies.  It's
not even helped by, I don't know, the
auto industry which has a very big problem
and then somehow Tesla is included as a
car seller in this story
which is ultimately
Tesla's main income line, although it is clear that
other areas and new income lines are developing very well
.  How did you view the
Tesla report?  because we know that you've been following
Tesla and paying attention to it for a very long
time.
Yes, I was expecting a weak report.  I
expected massive investments made by
Elon Musk because he announced early on
that he would build a Terafab, rebuild
one of the facilities to develop the
Optimus robot there.
is in the process of getting
capital markets and
investors used to the fact that Tesla is no longer a
simple car manufacturer, but is a
company of AI, robots, energy and so
on.  Yes, artificial
intelligence.
Now,
if we take into account the investments that are
currently being made and at some point the
fact that what these
investments that are being made now will produce will
very quickly enter the share price,
yes, I expect that in the short term the
share price will be impacted due to
the ratings received from
analysts, the decreasing target price
, the decreasing rating.  Yes.
But later,
after the current correction, Tesla
will experience
explosive growth again.
It's only when we are
Tesla investors that we realize
that we have an extremely
volatile stock in our portfolio.  There is no such
thing.  Every year, Tesla has a
50% drop from top to bottom,
and there hasn't been a year in which Tesla has
n't dropped by 50% from top to bottom.
If we take into account that the
share price reached $490, $480,
$490, that means $
280, $300, almost $250,
not $300, $250.  So Tesla can go
to $250 during the period when we
expect a correction across the
entire market, that is, in August,
September.  Can it go up to 250?
Yes, it can go.  We need to
realize this.  We need to be
prepared for the pain that comes to the
portfolio when you own Tesla.
Anyone who has not created the position
has a new opportunity to
create a significant position on Tesla.
But
for those of us who have the position created, we
just have to accept the pain of
going through this new delicate episode.   That's
all.  I also brought a report that
was a
hit, so to speak, the
IBM report, a report that before we had it
, IBM shouted profit
warning, raised the red flag and
said be careful, we expect a slightly
weaker report.  Now that the report has come out, we
have realized
its magnitude.  I do
n't know if I expected the report to be
weaker, but it's pretty weak for IBM.  It's
weak for the expectations
IBM created.  Not necessarily because of how it
looks, but because of the expectations that
were created based on how the
report looks.  And then I'm very curious
that the report itself raises some
suspicions towards the entire
technology industry, IBM being a Titan company
in this area, one of the
largest companies in the past was the
largest at a certain point.  Now it's
clear that it's a much older,
much slower company, but when you
see problems at this level with
IBM, and we'll immediately discuss
Oracle, somehow the market wonders
if the technology area
is a bit inflated.
It is very clear that IBM's stock has
benefited from exponential growth,
especially when the
United States came along and announced that they would
invest in the area of ​​Quantum Computing.
Investing in this area with IBM at the
forefront of Quantum Computing,
I think the stock has grown faster
than the company has come up with some
positive results.
And this report did nothing
but clarify the fact that the action went uphill
too quickly for the
horses to pull that cart uphill
.
Yes, I made a joke like that, sorry if
this joke is out of place,
but I think there are other companies with
prospects whose share price
has also grown very aggressively and are holding up
because they are in a
phase of explosive growth.  They are
high growth companies.  While IBM doesn't
seem to me to be a high growth company, it seems to me to
be a company that has been
revitalized by this market attention
[snoring] towards semiconductors and
by the American state that has come to
announce a massive investment in the area of
quantum computing and those quantum computers
that [snoring] IBM is developing
have benefited from
part of that budget allocated by the
United States, by the United States.  That's
all.  For now, I wouldn't buy
IBM no matter how much it drops, just as I
wouldn't buy other companies no matter
how much they drop.  I don't know, I mean
Adobe, I mean Intuit, I mean
Sales Force, even Oracle
scares me a little in terms of debt.  It's like I would
n't touch it no matter how
much it dropped.  There are other companies
that have declined, maybe will decline further,
but that are of much more
interest to me.  Yes.
IBM is not one of them.
Ironing time you mentioned earlier.
He receives a 7 billion contract with the
Pentagon to revitalize the
action a little more.  An action that I can say has
collapsed.  I mean, what is the decrease
?  I think I'm putting it a bit in
this collapse zone because the
decline when you exceed 60% in the price of a
share now,
especially
when the fundamentals are, I
think, not necessarily deeply negative,
but doubtful, with many suspicions, we
can declare that, no, Orăcăl has
some problems, somewhere at 64% the decline
and it doesn't seem at all close to being
completed as long as
they don't come to mention to us that they would
stop investing, they would stop
having an increased capex.  I was looking for an
investor.  I was looking
at Oracle because I was curious why I saw her
so negatively.  I'm saying now when you have 150
billion in debt, three or four
quarters, excuse me, with negative free cash flow
,
now I can't see you very
well.  I can't see you with good eyes
because it seems to me that the risk is starting to
increase so much that the
potential profit is no longer
justified.
And then what I would like to debate in the
context of the Pentagon offering this
contract, how do you see the situation at Oracle?
How problematic do you think
this debt situation is, which, if I'm not
mistaken, Google recently
increased in order to
invest heavily in the area of
artificial intelligence?  At the same
time, a gentleman who shorted Oracle,
named Michael Băi, has been
showing us lately that his shorts are
performing and that the people who didn't
trust him when he had an
investment fund were a little wrong, at least
for a moment.   He
mentioned to us that many of
these companies introduce
investments in
chips from Nividia or chips from
AMD or so on in their financial reports as
amortization in five to six years, as they do not have a
similar lifespan.   Yes.
And then in this whole context, I would like you to
tell me through your experience how
you see the oracle and if you could draw a
parallel with what you saw in the past,
what moment would you liken the oracle to and when
exactly can we raise
the bar for this, I don't know,
problematic company?
It's very hard to figure out what
I could compare Oracle's fix to
and the situation Oracle is in now,
because it's a delicate situation.
Oracle is really having a meltdown
because 64% on such a company
is a meltdown.  If it was 64% on Oclo, there
was no problem.  It was just a correction
.  A CL can go up to 90% with
correction.  Yes, but Oracle is having a
stock price crash.
Can the action still be collected from here?  Yes, it
can go up to $80, $70.  It can go
pretty low, but as long as
this danger exists,
I wouldn't go near that action.
How would you describe the danger for someone
who wants to be an ORCL investor?  Now,
although we don't feel this, the danger
could be represented by the
stock remaining at this
corrected price for a long time, meaning
entering now, the
stock correcting another 20%, 30% and staying here
for a long time.  This is a
pretty big danger because at some point he
will get bored with the stock and
sell at a loss.  I would advise
investors to look at
very important companies, companies with a
good cash flow situation.  Even if we
look at this area of ​​the Magnificent 7
and see that they are also making
massive investments, companies like Google,
Amazon, Meta are still much better than an
Oracle.  I have a
Tesla under a certain price.  Yes,
they are much better.  Even Nvidia if it
corrects below $170.
Whether AMD corrects from this level
towards $450, maybe even less, we don't
know.  There are much better and
better positioned companies than Oracle.  You can't
risk investing in a company that
has enormous debts, even if it
could have some
very important contracts.  Just like
you said, these contracts span
several years.  The revenue, for
example the Orcăl contract, these 7
billion are not all recognized in
2026. They are recognized year by year as part
of that 7 billion contract.  So you can't
come and say now that
7 billion appears in your balance sheet.  There is no
such thing.  Only the part that the respective
state department
, the Pentagon, or whoever signed the
contract with them for this year appears.  Yes, it
will be very, very difficult for
Oracle stock to return to the
prices it was at.  We made a
good decision to get out when we
had to.  I rode the wave with a
lazy hour for $300.  We thanked
Larry Ellison profusely for what he
offered us,
but we
also backed down
and backed down.  We moved on with the
pennies in different positions
because we are in the capital market to
make money.  We are not in the
capital market to fall in love with a company
or a CEO.
Absolute.   Yes.
We are here to figure out
where in the near,
medium and long term future our money will
multiply as safely and as much as
possible.  But
what we say now about Oracle
can change overnight in the context
where the business strategy
offered by Larry Ellison
suddenly changes and these investments
suddenly end up being told by Oracle that they don't
know, they've decreased by 80% and they say we're
cutting investments because we realize there's
a problem.
When you get into a game like this, you can't really back down
.   That's
clear.  Yes.  When you start
investing and want to hold an
important position in the artificial
intelligence area, you can't really back
down because it's like you've
given up on all your previous investments
and taken on some
very large debts.  You see, it's in
vain.  I mean, you don't see a situation
similar to what Meta was like when he
gave up the metaverse.  I don't really see that
.  I don't really see the same thing.
Even Meta cannot come now and
say, "Okay, we are completely cutting investments in the
IAI area."  They don't have to continue
this.  These investments will be
part of the
company's future development for
many years to come.  And then
based on what we discussed earlier, I can't help but
ask you
how you view the emergence of Kimia AI Kimia
Ai K3 from China, the first competitive model
since the dipsic, a model that once
again appears at a time when the
American market is at its peak and basically what is
happening?
This supremacy that
Antropic Open may Grock on some
levels, perhaps Google Gemini, perhaps more
recently Musei from Meta, may end up
having in relation to the Chinese competition, is being contested.  And
when this happens,
the most problematic situation is
that
the models in China did not have the capex that
America has, not even
close.  I mean, if we look at America,
we see hundreds of billions.  Models in
China are made for tens of
billions.
Now with the reservation that this is the
public data provided by these
companies.  Now doubtful.
We know we are talking about China, we know we are talking
about a system closer to
communism.  Those of the second generation,
older than me, who caught
communism, know how
, during Ceaușescu's working visits,
everything had to be on point.  That's what
reports
from China sometimes seem like.  And then I want to ask you
how you see this impact brought by
language models in China in a
context in which
suspicions are raised towards many
investments in the area of
artificial intelligence and many companies, including
Oracle, which we discussed earlier.
Yes, it seems that the Chinese can achieve
more with less
and it is possible that all these
American companies that invest a lot in the
semiconductor area for
the development of certain
language models will at some point
realize that these investments were
made on chips that are outdated
because we will evolve
technologically and other chips will be created.
Elon Musk even pointed out that
his new production facility, the new Terafab,
will produce much more
efficient chips.
What happens when
much more efficient chips catch up with the
old chips for which these
companies continue to pay a lot of money?
And how do you change its
infrastructure when you've
already created, I don't know, all the
infrastructure on GPUs from
NVIDIA, how did you end up integrating, I don't
know, a new chip that's different
hardware, different networking, totally
different?
Yes, it's a big question mark and we'll
see how these things develop
in the future.  I already believe
that the semiconductor cycle
will stop at some point.  We will have
a correction
and a subsequent consolidation in the
lower area of ​​the correction and only later, in
maybe another six months, eight months, a
year, will a new
growth cycle begin again on Nvidia, Broadcom,
AMD and other companies, but it is quite possible
that at some point, after this boom,
a correction cycle will appear on
semiconductors.  And the Chinese are raising a
very big alarm bell because
they solve a problem much more cheaply
than the Americans do.
You've probably seen the famous interview
with Chamad Bali Habidia, I hope I
pronounced it right, Chamat, who was VP
at Meta in and a very
big investor in technology.  It premiered
on
CNBC, if I'm not mistaken, and he talked
about this
computational capacity that this
language model offers us, how much we pay
for it, and to imagine it as in
a barrel of oil, a barrel.  And he said
that if Antropic
gives it to us for $26, Open gives it to us for $21. He was saying
some prices.  I remember he said
about
Google when they give
$1.5 for 1 vir and $1 for meta.  Now I don't know the
exact numbers, but somehow it was in this area that it was
referred to.  The Chinese can give it to us
at 0.5.  [laughter]
You know?  And then looking at it this way, you
have to ask yourself a
question, not necessarily whether the things are
suspicious in the technology area, but
how they managed to do this with
much lower costs, how they keep the
costs so low.  And then
often the answer is the
same as in the auto industry, that they are
heavily funded and helped by the
Chinese state, which ultimately has some
data-level interests in these
models.
Yes, that's one thing, but from my point of
view, what China is doing is good
for America and for us because it
forces Americans to be
increasingly efficient and productive as well
.  Very right.   I
mean, when you don't have a
competitor, you can leave it like that, look what I've
achieved, I'm the best, but
when you see that the competition is coming
after you and at lower costs,
this aspect forces
you to be more and more competitive,
to come with lower and lower prices
and to have better and better production
.  Yes.  o increasingly
greater efficiency.  We'll see how
things develop, but I say there will be a
very big fight between China and America, in the
area of ​​technology, in the area of ​​space.
And this is good for us as
investors because it forces
Americans to print more and more
money and make larger and
larger investments to keep up with China,
which is coming pretty hard.
Dear friends, we close as always with
Romania.  If you saw me talking
a little more in this video when
we were trying to compensate for the
problem that
my health has,
yes, that Valentin has, I mean I didn't start
talking more out of the blue
, but it was a situation in which we
tried to have the
best possible video, but not [laughter] not to
have any problems because Valentina has
this situation.  I want to talk, to
close with Romania.
Tell me, please, what you think about
these people who are currently convincing us
that real estate is still
okay.  I mean, we see problems like this,
declining GDP, technical recession, we don't
know what
the ratings offered will be like in the end, and so
on.
Political issues.
Political issues.  The first time the
banks were
finally probably in agreement with
them being hit
by this tax.
Mr. Isăresc is making
supernatural efforts to keep the
RON exchange rate with the euro.
From this whole context,
people who sell real estate generally come to
say: Well, yes, they have decreased demand a
lot.  Oh, there's no more offers. And now
I guess they're
right somewhere.  There is no longer
such a wide offer because
developers have not really developed, they have not
built so much
lately because they have not really
offered construction licenses.
Easy, easy, from my point of view, in
this area of ​​construction,
whoever issues the construction licenses, the
construction permits,
excuse me,
will do everything possible to concentrate
these construction permits only
to certain large developers.
Smaller developers or those who were
building a block or two will gradually disappear from the market. In short, it
was a golden period in this area of
real estate development in our country, in which
many became rich in
two or three years because they started
building blocks and houses.
Slowly, the area will be cleared and
only large developers will remain, and only
they will receive
construction permits.
I would say at this point that those who
keep promoting this real estate area, the
real estate area, yes,
real estate sales, are pursuing their own interests.  It's
normal for them to present things as being under
control, that things are looking good, that yes,
they are selling, good locations are selling, they are
[snoring] I would say they are not really
selling.
All the data coming to us now.  I don't
want people to look at us because
every time we talk about Romania,
somehow we talk [snoring] about the things that
ultimately reach us from the field
and there are a lot of notaries who
tell us that not so many are signing anymore and
Yes.  Yes, you have to do
these things.  At the same time, I see that
if our interest rate fluctuates so much
and we don't know exactly what the price will be,
this variation in inflation, not the price in
SIM, but it seems like they're still going up.
We can see interest rate increases, we can
see more defaults on
loans, meaning people who unfortunately are no
longer able to pay their installments.  That is,
we can see some unpleasant situations
that can very easily end up in a
negative spiral.
Absolute.  There are a lot of people who
don't want very many anymore, not very
many, but there will be people who won't be
able to pay the installments because they will
lose their jobs.   There
are many who took rates that were much too
high because they were in industries that were
doing very well at the time
.  I look at the IT industry, which is
suffering in some places.  I mean, we have to
call things by their proper names.
Those people, if they are fired and don't
find a job within, say, three to six
months.  That's right.  Plus there
is another situation.
Many locations, for example, in the
Mamaia, Mamaia Nord area, but also in
Bucharest, and other large cities, were
sold for cash.  Now
this can't really be done anymore and all
transactions are made through the bank with the entire
transfer amount, and many people don't really have the
money in the bank, in their account to make a
transfer, to pay by
bank transfer.  The transactions of the last
period, the last two or three years,
which led to an explosion in the
real estate sector and very large profits
made by some and others, are not really
happening anymore.  Right now, there are a lot of
people buying to
flip, right?  They would buy from the
project area to add to the
gray or red area or whatever
other
phase of construction the
building was in, and sell it at a profit.
At the moment, even a large
part of those people no longer buy
to flip, because they
realize that there is no more money to be made.
Given this situation in
real estate, it is clear that several sectors
of our economy tend to
have problems.  I also saw the
catering area, meaning there are still
negative aspects.
What we expect is that once
some money comes from the European Union,
they can unblock things, but
we see that we don't really fit into
these anymore.  We're seeing how all of this plays out
in the local economy and we'll keep you
posted.  We are trying to
be as transparent as possible here and to
talk about these things
through the eyes of people who are
economists, who are talking about some problems
that they see today and will
happen in a year, two or so
.  Because remember at the
beginning when Valentin was talking to us about and
we were talking a lot about this problem
that the
Romanian economy was going to have.  Well, it was nowhere to be seen.
Well, there was total joy in the market.   It
seemed very similar to a moment
I had in my family when
someone from my family said to me:
What a crisis, Alex, around
2012-2014 when the crisis in
Greece was coming.  What crisis ends with
this nonsense leading to the best moments of
our lives and then came the one I
felt for eight years.   It seemed to
me that 2025 in Romania was a similar situation
and it seemed to me that the world wasn't paying attention to
it and that's why we were debating it so much
here.  Dear friends, this was
this week's material.   We
would like to thank you very much
if you have followed it this far.  Give us
a like and a subscribe if you appreciate the
content we make.  We
thank our members for always seeing them
in the comments area and for
trying to push
this video into the YouTube algorithm.  We would also like to thank
our production, which
last time had a pretty good title,
anticipating a problem in the
financial market that
seems to be coming in the coming months.
All the best and thank you.
Thank you too and I apologize for the
state I found myself in today.  See you
next week.